Dr Rustom: Atah ṣaḍaṅganyāsa.
Dr Rustom : Atah ṣaḍaṅganyāsa.
Now we purify the six parts of the body.
Nous purifions les six parties du corps.
Shri Mataji: Yes, we have to clear the six parts of our body.
Shri Mataji : Oui, nous devons purifier les six parties de notre corps.
Dr Rustom: First, the heart.
Dr Rustom : Tout d'abord, le cœur.
Shri Mataji: To the heart.
Shri Mataji : Au cœur.
Dr Rustom: OM bhur bhuva swaha hitayaya namah
Dr Rustom : OM bhur bhuva swaha hitayaya namah
Dr Rustom: Next the top of the head.
Dr Rustom : Puis, le sommet de la tête.
Shri Mataji: That is, we bow to our heart.
Shri Mataji : Nous nous inclinons devant notre cœur.
Dr Rustom: OM bhur bhuva swaha shirse swaha
Dr Rustom : OM bhur bhuva swaha shirse swaha.
Shri Mataji: Sahasrara.
Shri Mataji : Sahasrara.
Dr Rustom: Then the Back Agnya.
Dr Rustom : Puis l'Agnya arrière.
OM bhur bhuva swaha shikayaya vashat
OM bhur bhuva swaha shikayaya vashat.
Shri Mataji: ‘Vashat’ is like this. [Shri Mataji claps her hands]
Shri Mataji : « Vashat » se fait comme ceci. [Frappe des mains]
That means you bring two fingers, bring it round and hit it hard,
Cela signifie que vous prenez deux doigts, vous tournez et vous frappez fort,
on the Sahasrara [on the palm of the hand].
sur le Sahasrara [de la main].
That is taking out the baddha, you see.
Cela permet d'éliminer le baddha, vous voyez.
From here, take it out and put it on the Sahasrara, hit it hard.
De là, vous l'enlevez et vous le placez sur le Sahasrara, frappez fort.
And this is the ‘Samhara Shakti’ of Shri Krishna [destructive power].
Et c'est le « Samhara Shakti » de Shri Krishna [pouvoir destructeur].
Dr Rustom: OM bhur bhuva swaha kavacha aham
Dr Rustom : OM bhur bhuva swaha kavacha aham.
Shri Mataji: Kavach. Kavach is bandhan.
Shri Mataji : Kavach. Kavach est bandhan.
Dr Rustom: OM bhur bhuva swaha netrayaa vashat
Dr Rustom : OM bhur bhuva swaha netrayaa vashat.
Again, with the clean eyes you again go back at the Agnya, at the Back and take it down.
Encore une fois, avec les yeux purs, vous retournez à l'Agnya,
Dr Rustom: OM bhur bhuva swaha astra vaphat.
Dr Rustom : OM bhur bhuva swaha astra vaphat.
Shri Mataji: Astra. Astra are the weapons that you have got. Astra vaphat!
Shri Mataji : Astra. Astra sont les armes que vous avez. Astra vaphat !
[Shri Mataji claps]. Means all the baddhas should run away.
Cela signifie que tous les baddhas doivent s'enfuir.
Dr Rustom: Now the bandhan: ‘Iti dig bandhan’.
Dr Rustom : Maintenant, le bandhan : « Iti dig bandhan ».
[Shri Mataji speaks in Hindi]
[Shri Mataji parle en hindi]
Shri Mataji: Kavach – Kavach is the cover, Kavach is the cover.
Shri Mataji : Kavach – Kavach est la protection, Kavach est la protection.
Dr Rustom: Shield like.
Dr Rustom : Un bouclier.
Shri Mataji: Shield, shield, shield, Kavach. Kavach is shield, sorry. Kavach is shield!
Shri Mataji : Bouclier, bouclier, bouclier, Kavach. Kavach est un bouclier !
Dr Rustom: Rigvedah, yejurvedah, sam-vedah yatharvana
Dr Rustom : Rigvedah, yejurvedah, sam-vedah yatharvana
angeshcha sahitah sarve kalasham tu samashritah
angeshcha sahitah sarve kalasham tu samashritah
Atra gayatri savitri shanti pushti kare tatha ayantu deva pujarthan durita kshayakarakaha.
Atra gayatri savitri shanti pushti kare tatha ayantu deva pujarthan durita kshayakarakaha.